stuff.co.nz 2019-06-26

# Privacy Policy | Stuff.co.nz

This website is owned and operated by Stuff Limited. In this policy, "us", "we" or "our" means Stuff Limited and its related bodies corporate. 

This policy addresses the following:    
* [How do we collect, hold, use or disclose personal information?](http://www.stuff.co.nz/about-stuff/10648385/Privacy-Policy#disclose)  
* [What happens if we are not able to collect personal information?](http://www.stuff.co.nz/about-stuff/10648385/Privacy-Policy#whathappens)  
* [Will my personal information be disclosed outside New Zealand?](http://www.stuff.co.nz/about-stuff/10648385/Privacy-Policy#newzealand)  

We are bound by the New Zealand Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1993 (Act) (subject to exemptions that apply to us under that Act) 1993. From time to time, due to the nature of our business activities, we will handle personal information relying on the media exemption in the Act where appropriate. Where we do so, we will ensure that we comply with the New Zealand Press Council Privacy Principles. If you require more information on the collection and use of personal information in the course of journalism, please visit the Privacy Commissioner Website at <http://privacy.org.nz/>

We may, from time to time, review and update this policy, including taking account of new or amended laws, new technology and/or changes to our operations. All personal information held by us will be governed by the most recently updated policy. Your privacy matters to us, so whether you are new to Stuff or are a long time user, please take the time to get to know our practices.

**WHAT IS CONSIDERED PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

When used in this policy, the term "personal information" has the meaning given to it in the Act. In general terms, it is any information that can be used to personally identify you. This may include (but is not limited to) your name, age, gender, postcode and contact details (including phone numbers and email addresses) and possibly financial information, including your credit card, direct debit or PayPal account information. If the information we collect personally identifies you, or you are reasonably identifiable from it, the information will be considered personal information.

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOLD?**

We may collect the following types of personal information:  
name;  
mailing or street address;  
email address;  
telephone number;  
age or birth date;  
profession, occupation or job title;  
details of the products and services you have purchased from us or which you have enquired about, together with any additional information necessary to deliver those products and services and to respond to your enquiries;  
any additional information relating to you that you provide to us directly through our websites or indirectly through use of our website or online presence through our representatives or otherwise; and   
information you provide to us through our service centre, customer surveys or visits by our representatives from time to time.

**COOKIES**

In some cases we may also collect your personal information through the use of cookies. When you access our website, we may send a "cookie" (which is a small summary file containing a unique ID number) to your computer. This enables us to recognise your computer and greet you each time you visit our website, without bothering you with a request to register or login. It also helps us keep track of products or services you view, so that we can send you news about those products or services. 

We also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, to determine which areas of our websites have been visited, and to measure transaction patterns in the aggregate. We use this to research our users' habits so that we can improve our online products and services. 

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you can set your browser so that your computer does not accept them. We may also log IP addresses (the electronic addresses of computers connected to the internet) to analyse trends, administer the website, track user movements, and gather broad demographic information.

We may also collect anonymous data (which is not personal information) relating to your activity on our websites (including IP addresses) via cookies, or we may collect information from you in response to a survey. We generally use this information to report statistics, analyse trends, administer our services, diagnose problems and target and improve the quality of our products and services. To the extent this information does not constitute personal information because it does not identify you or anyone else, the New Zealand Privacy Principles do not apply and we may use this information for any purpose and by any means whatsoever.

**HOW DO WE COLLECT, HOLD, USE OR DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We collect your personal information directly from you unless it is unreasonable or impractical to do so. 

We do this in ways including:  
through your access and use of our website, apps or sending SMS/MMS to us;  
through someone else who has provided us with your information (e.g. a gift subscription);  
during conversations between you and our representatives; and  
when you complete an application or purchase order.

We may also collect personal information from third parties including:  
third party companies such as credit reporting agencies, law enforcement agencies and other government entities;  
advertisers;  
mailing lists;  
recruitment agencies;  
contractors and business partners.

**WHY DO WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

The primary purpose for which we collect information about you is to enable us to perform our business activities and functions and to provide the best possible quality of customer service. We collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information for the following purposes:

to provide products and services to you;  
to provide you with news, information or advice about our existing and new products and services;  
to communicate with you including by email, mail or telephone;  
to manage and enhance our products and services;  
to personalise and customise your experience;  
to provide you with access to protected areas of our websites;  
to conduct competitions or promotions on behalf of Stuff and selected third parties;  
to verify your identity;  
to provide as part of business data to third parties if you have authorised us to do so;  
to conduct business processing functions for operation of our websites or our business;  
for our administrative, marketing (including direct marketing), promotional, planning, product/service development, quality control and research purposes, or those of our contractors or external service providers;  
to provide your updated personal information to us, our contractors or external service providers;  
to investigate any complaints about or made by you, or if we have reason to suspect that you are in breach of any of our terms and conditions or that you are or have been otherwise engaged in any unlawful activity; and/or  
as required or permitted by any law (including the Privacy Act).  
Your personal information will not be shared, sold, rented or disclosed other than as described in this Privacy Policy.

**WHAT HAPPENS IF WE CAN'T COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

If you do not provide us with the personal information described in this policy, some or all of the following may happen:

we may not be able to provide you with the products or services you requested, either to the same standard, or at all (for example, if you do not register as a member of a website, you will not be able to access features or services that are reserved for members only);  
we may not be able to provide you with information about products and services that you may want, including information about discounts, sales or special promotions; or  
we may be unable to tailor the content of our websites to your preferences and your experience of our websites may not be as enjoyable or useful.

**HOW DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We may disclose your personal information to:  
our employees, related bodies corporate, contractors or external service providers for the operation of our websites or our business, fulfilling requests by you, and otherwise provide products and services to you, including without limitation, web hosting providers, IT systems administrators, mailing houses, newsagents, couriers, payment processors, photographic analysers, data entry service providers, electronic network administrators, debt collectors, and professional advisers such as accountants, solicitors, business advisors and consultants;  
our existing or potential agents, business partners or joint venture entities or partners;  
our sponsors, or promoters of any competition that we conduct or promote via our services;  
specific third parties authorised by you to receive information held by us;  
the police, any relevant authority or enforcement body, or your Internet Service Provider or network administrator, for example, if we have reason to suspect that you have committed a breach of any of our terms and conditions, or have otherwise been engaged in any unlawful activity, and we reasonably believe that disclosure is necessary;  
as required or permitted by any law (including the Privacy Act).

**Direct marketing materials**

We may send you direct marketing communications and information about products and services that we consider may be of interest to you. These communications may be sent in various forms, including mail, SMS or email, in accordance with applicable marketing laws. If you indicate a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavour to use that method whenever practical to do so. 

In addition, at any time, you may opt out of receiving marketing communications from us by contacting us (details below) or by using the opt-out facilities provided (e.g. an unsubscribe link), or by updating your personal details on our Member Centre webpage using the link provided on this page (you may also cancel your profile using the Member Centre). We will then ensure that your name is removed from our mailing list. We do not provide your personal information to other organisations for the purposes of direct marketing unless expressly authorised by you. 

If you receive communications from us that you believe have been sent to you other than in accordance with this policy, or in breach of any law, please contact us using the details provided below.

**HOW CAN I ACCESS AND CORRECT MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?  **

You may request access to any personal information we hold about you at any time by contacting us (details below). Where we hold information that you are entitled to access, we will try to provide you with suitable means of accessing it (for example, by mailing or emailing it to you). 

We will not charge for simply making a request and will not charge for making any corrections to your personal information. If you make an access request, we will ask you to verify your identity. There may be instances where we cannot grant you access to the personal information we hold. For example, we may need to refuse access if granting access would interfere with the privacy of others, or if it would result in a breach of confidentiality. If that happens, we will give you written reasons for any refusal.

If you believe that personal information we hold about you is incorrect, incomplete or inaccurate, then you may request us to amend it. We will consider if the information requires amendment. If we do not agree that there are grounds for amendment, then we will add a note to the personal information stating that you disagree with it. Members of our websites will generally be able to access and update their membership details online. We request that you keep your information as current as possible so that we may continue to improve our service to you.

**HOW YOU I COMPLAIN ABOUT A BREACH OF PRIVACY?**

If you believe your privacy has been breached by us, or have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us using the contact information below and provide details of the incident so that we can investigate it. 

We have a formal procedure for investigating and dealing with privacy breaches. Once the Privacy Officer receives a complaint, whether it is in writing or by verbal means, the Privacy Officer will commence an investigation with the relevant business unit from which the alleged breach stemmed. The investigator will endeavour to determine the nature of the breach and how it occurred. 

We may contact you during the process to seek any further clarification if necessary. If a breach is found, the Privacy Officer will escalate the matter to management so that the process can be rectified to prevent any further breaches from taking place. We will also contact you to inform you of the outcome of the investigation. We will endeavour to resolve all investigations within a reasonable time.

We will treat your requests or complaints confidentially. Our representative will contact you within a reasonable time after receipt of your complaint to discuss your concerns and outline options regarding how they may be resolved. We will aim to ensure that your complaint is resolved in a timely and appropriate manner. 

Please contact our Privacy Officer at:   
Privacy Officer   
Stuff Limited   
Post: 42 -52 Willis Street, Wellington, PO Box 2595, Wellington   
Email: [privacy@stuff.co.nz](mailto:privacy@stuff.co.nz)

**WILL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION BE DISCLOSED OUTSIDE NEW ZEALAND?**

We may disclose personal information to our related bodies corporate and external service providers located overseas for some of the purposes listed above. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the overseas recipients of your personal information do not breach the privacy obligations relating to your personal information.   
We may disclose your personal information to entities located outside of New Zealand, including the following:  
our related bodies corporate, located in Australia and south-east Asia;  
our data hosting and Cloud-based IT service providers;  
other external service providers located in the Philippines and United States; and  
other third parties operating in jurisdictions including China, India, Indonesia, New Zealand, Hong Kong and the United States where you have authorised us to do so.

**SECURITY**

We will take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information that we hold from misuse, loss, or unauthorised access, including by means of firewalls, password access, secure servers and encryption of credit card transactions.   
If you suspect any misuse or loss of, or unauthorised access to, your personal information, please let us know immediately.

**LINKS**

Our website may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. We make no representations or warranties in relation to the privacy practices of any third party website and we are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of any third party website. Third party websites are responsible for informing you about their own privacy practices.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. Any updated versions of this privacy policy will be posted on our website. This privacy policy was last updated in February 2018.

**Stuff Tracking and Targeting Policy**

Stuff Limited (we, us or our) collects data about your browsing activity on our network. We may also use non-personal information that we collect about you on our network to identify you on third party websites where we have an arrangement in place to serve ads on those third party websites. We may also collect anonymous internet usage data from third parties.

One of the reasons we collect usage data is to display targeted advertisements or content on our network and also on third party websites. For that purpose, usage data is collected and assigned to one or more pre-defined categories (for example "holiday seekers"). If this infers a particular interest, a cookie is placed in your web browser which may determine the type of targeted advertising or content that you receive. We target advertisements and content in order to improve your user experience, so that you are served advertisements and content that we believe may be more relevant or useful to you.

To create consumer profiles we also collate anonymous data from other sources across our network, including memberships, surveys or competitions. However, we will not combine usage data with your personal information (as defined in the Privacy Act 1993), or share your personal information with any third party, except in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 and our Privacy Policy.

Advertisements or content may also be "targeted" to users based on:   
the type of content displayed on a given web page;  
the geographical location of a user (i.e. identified by an IP address); or  
specific searches undertaken by a user.  
Other reasons we may collect anonymous usage data include:   
to limit the number of times users are served certain ads;  
to monitor the performance of advertising campaigns;  
to audit, research, and analyse usage in order to maintain and improve our services, and to develop new services; and  
to ensure that our ad-serving technologies function properly.

We will not collect usage data or target advertisements based on the following market segments: 

racial or ethnic origin; or  
political opinions; or  
membership of a political association; or  
religious beliefs or affiliations; or  
philosophical beliefs; or  
membership of a professional or trade association; or  
membership of a trade union; or  
sexual preferences or practices; or  
criminal record; or  
health information; or  
genetic information that is not otherwise health information.

If we ever seek to target advertisements based on the above market segments, we will first obtain your express consent.

We will not create categories designed to target children under the age of 13 years (however, this does not prevent us from marketing children's products to an adult audience).

Third party advertisers purchase advertising products from us that enable them to target particular types of users of our network, for advertisements served both on our network and also on third party websites.

In some cases we permit advertisers to embed their own cookies in advertisements subject to our standard advertising terms and conditions. Generally, advertisers will embed cookies in advertisements to monitor the performance of their advertising campaign, but they may also collect anonymous usage data relating to browsing activity on our network. 

We do not, however, permit advertisers to use any usage data obtained from our network to target advertisements or content to users off our network. We encourage advertisers to have a privacy policy that outlines their data collection activities and usage. Please refer to such third party privacy policies for more information.

We will not provide any personal information to an advertiser or any other third party without your express consent or in accordance with our Privacy Policy. However, to the extent that anonymous user data does not constitute personal information, we are entitled to deal with that information in any manner we see fit.

We have worked alongside other leading industry players and industry associations in New Zealand to develop the New Zealand Best Practice Guideline for Online Behavioral Advertising to guide participants who offer Third Party Online Behavioural Advertising ("OBA") and promote consumer control and transparency of how data is collected. [A copy can be accessed here](http://www.youronlinechoices.co.nz/images/files/New_Zealand_Best_Practice_Guidelines_for_Online_Behavioural_Advertising_FINAL_FEB_2013.pdf).

"Third party" or "third parties", as referred to throughout this policy, means a non-Stuff entity or organisation that is engaged in OBA and collects and uses web viewing behaviour data for the purposes of OBA via our websites.  
"Third Party OBA" occurs when browsing behaviour off our network is used to deliver behavioural advertisements on our network. 

The Guidelines set out self-regulatory principles designed to promote transparency, consumer awareness and consumer choice in relation to the type of advertising consumers receive and to encourage good practice and accountability in businesses that deploy Third Party OBA.

We adhere to industry "best practice" for the storage of anonymous usage data. Security firewall, data encryption, and authorisation access are used to safeguard data held by us.

Stuff uses Adobe Audience Manager ("AAM") technology and cookies to serve interest-based advertising. AAM offers consumers the opportunity to select a persistent opt-out cookie to prevent information from being uniquely associated with their browsers. This way, a user can opt out of AAM cookies without erasing or altering other cookies associated with a browser. To opt out of AAM cookies, you can go to <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4>, and click on the "Opt Out" button.

We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Tracking and Targeting Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

Opting out means that the display advertising you see on our network may not be tailored to your interests or preferences on the web browser you are using. Anonymous usage data may, however, continue to be collected by us for other purposes (including those outlined above).

You can also manage cookies in your web browser privacy settings. See [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com.au/opt-out/) for more information.

For more information regarding how we treat personal information and, in some cases, non-personal information, please refer to our Privacy Policy.

For more information about this policy, or our tracking and targeting practices, or if you would like to make a complaint to us in connection with this policy, please send an email to [privacy@stuff.co.nz](mailto:privacy@stuff.co.nz). 

If you would like to make a complaint in connection with Third Party OAB, you can also go to Your Online Choices.

Stuff Limited, Spark Central, 42-52 Willis Street, Wellington, New Zealand.
